<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Libav Tutorial on danielxhogan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/libav-tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Libav Tutorial on danielxhogan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 12:23:33 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tutorials/libav-tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lesson 1.1: Remux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/libav-tutorial/lesson-1.1-remux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 12:23:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/libav-tutorial/lesson-1.1-remux/</guid>
      
      <description>In this lesson, you will learn how to use Libav to remux a video file. You will learn about the AVFormatContext struct that is used for muxing and demuxing, you will learn how to open an output file and prepare it for storing video and audio streams, and you will learn how to read packets of data from an input and write them to an output. All the code for this tutorial can found here.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lesson 0: Libav Tutorial Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/libav-tutorial/lesson-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 10:50:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/libav-tutorial/lesson-0/</guid>
      
      <description>Welcome to the Libav Tutorial! This tutorial will show you how to use the Libav library in C to process video files. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t assume any prior knowledge of the library but it does assume anyone following this tutorial is familiar with FFmpeg, C, general video/audio concepts, and general programming concepts.
The first section of this tutorial will be all about remuxing. It will go through examples that show how to perform various operations on video files without encoding or decoding such as reformatting, copying and editing metadata, adding chapters, adding subtitles, combining streams from multiple input files, and seperating streams into multiple ouput files.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
